Guide to the Account Books Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- VOLUMES, 1680-1919; Series I; 42 linear feet (100 boxes)
  - Scheiter, H.R.
    See: box 139, folder 686
  - Scovill, Linus, 1837-1866 (Box 66, Folder 363)
  - Seaman, John
  - Sedgewick and Porter, 1836-1841 (Box 66, Folder 364)
  - Seeley, Bennett, 1858-1874 (Box 66, Folder 365)
  - Seward, David, 1761-1847 (Box 67, Folder 366)
  - Shelbon, Samuel, 1797-1815 (Box 67, Folder 367)
  - Shelton, Elijah E., 1833-1841 (Box 67, Folder 368)
  - Shelton, Joseph, 1721-1789 (Box 67, Folder 369)
    See also: box 140, folder 688
  - Shelton, Samuel Frederick, 1813-1815 (Box 67, Folder 370)
  - Sherman, Charles, 1806-1809 (Box 68, Folder 371)
  - Sloper, Georges, 1842-1859 (Box 68, Folder 372)
  - Simms, Ralph, 1836-1845 (Box 68, Folder 373)
  - Smith, George H.
    - Account book, 1835-1863 (Box 68, Folder 374)
    - Ledger, 1835-1853 (Box 68, Folder 375)
      See also: box 140, folder 689
  - Smith, Giles G. (Box 69, Folder 376)
  - Smith, Ralph Dunning, 1849-1857 (Box 69, Folder 377)
  - Smith, William R.
    - Daybook, 1829 (Box 69, Folder 378)
    - Ledger, 1832-1849 (Box 69, Folder 379)
      See also: box 79, folder 423-425
  - Smith and Cottrell, 1858
    - Daybook, 1856-1857 (Box 70, Folder 380)
  - Sovereign Trading Association, 1878-1887 (Box 70, Folder 381)
  - [Staniford, Mary Fay?], 1811-1830 (Box 70, Folder 382)
  - Stanton, Adam and Son, 1795-1808 (Box 70, Folder 383)
  - Stanton, John, 1764-1819 (Box 70, Folder 384)
  - Starkweather, James, 1788-1827 (Box 71, Folder 385)
  - Steele, Norman
    See: box 141, folder 693
  - Stevens, John, 1727-1733 (Box 71, Folder 386)
  - Stillman, Levi, 1815-1834 (Box 72, Folder 387)
  - Stratton, Seth L., 1854-1870 (Box 72, Folder 388)
  - Talcott, Abraham, 1782-1824 (Box 72, Folder 389)
  - Tallmadge, John and Company, 1800-1814 (Box 73, Folder 390)
    See also: box 141, folder 694
  - Tallmadge, Smith and Company, 1809-1861 (Box 73, Folder 391)
  - Tarby, Charles, 1894-1895 (Box 74, Folder 392)
  - Thayer and Simons, 1884 (Box 74, Folder 393)
  - Thompson, Moses
    See: box 142, folder 696
  - Thorpe, Eliaphalet, 1825-1845 (Box 74, Folder 394)
  - [Tinker, Lebbeus T.?], 1808-1809 (Box 75, Folder 395)
  - Toby, Egbert P., 1840-1847 (Box 75, Folder 396)
  - Todd, Alfred, 1861 (Box 75, Folder 397)
  - Todd, Ely
    - Account book, 1800-1815 (Box 76, Folder 398)
    - Loose papers, 1809-1811 (Box 76, Folder 399)
  - Todd, Thelus, 1802-1861 (Box 76, Folder 400)
  - Todd Brothers, 1885-1886 (Box 76, Folder 401)
  - Tomlinson, Wood and Company, 1842-1843 (Box 76, Folder 402)
  - Tucker, Reuben, 1814-1839 (Box 76, Folder 403)
  - Turnpikes Collection, 1811-1819 (Box 77, Folder 404-413)
  - [Tuttle, Charles Manning?]
    - Ledger, 1849 (Box 77, Folder 414)
    - Loose papers, 1849-1858 (Box 77, Folder 415)
  - Tweedy, R. and S.
    See: box 142, folder 697
  - Twichell, George H., 1845-1873 (Box 77, Folder 416)
  - Underhill, Richardson
    See: box 142, folder 698
  - United States Pine Company, 1800-1866 (Box 78, Folder 417)
  - U.S. Army Collection
    See: box 142, folder 699
  - [U.S. Patent Button, Rivet, Needle Machine Manufacturing Company?], 1869-1870 (Box 78, Folder 418)
  - Vose, Nathan
    See: box 143, folder 700
  - Wadsworth, Elijah and Company
    See: box 143, folder 701
  - Ward, Lewis, 1835-1840 (Box 78, Folder 419)
  - Wake, Nathaniel, 1738-1766 (Box 78, Folder 420)
  - Washband, Josiah
    See: box 143, folder 702
  - Watkinson, John R., 1819-1826 (Box 79, Folder 421)
  - Watson, Wellington
    - Daybooks, 1856-1859 (Box 79, Folder 422)
    - Ledgers, 1856-1864 (Box 79, Folder 423-425)
    - Loose papers, 1844-1864 (Box 79, Folder 426)
    - Pocket ledgers, 1855, 1860 (Box 79, Folder 427)
  - W. Watson and Sons, 1866-1871 (Box 80, Folder 428-433)
    See also: box 143, folder 703-704
  - Way and Peck
    - Daybooks, 1848-1869 (Box 81, Folder 434-436)
    - Ledgers, 1848-1869 (Box 82, Folder 437-438)
    - Ledgers, 1870-1884 (Box 83, Folder 439-440)
    - Loose papers, 1864-1884 (Box 83, Folder 441)
  - Webb (Walter) and Company
    See: box 143, folder 705
  - Webster, Nathaniel Sawyer, 1862 (Box 83, Folder 442)
  - Webster, Nathaniel, 1812-1819 (Box 84, Folder 443-446)
  - Wetmore, Frederick, 1868-1882 (Box 84, Folder 447)
  - Wheeler, William Henry, 1852-1886 (Box 85, Folder 448-450)
  - Whiting, Henry W.
    - Account book, 1865-1873 (Box 85, Folder 451)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 85, Folder 452)
    - Daybooks, 1856-1858 (Box 86, Folder 453-454)
    - Daybook, 1857 (Box 87, Folder 455)
    - Journal, 1856 (Box 87, Folder 456)
    - Ledger, 1856 (Box 88, Folder 457)
  - Whiting, Henry W. and Company
    - Accounts, 1855-1856 (Box 88, Folder 458)
    - Loose papers, 1880 (Box 88, Folder 459)
  - Whitney and Townshend
    See: box 144, folder 706
  - William, Amos
    See: box 144, folder 707-708
  - Williams, Harmon, undated (Box 89, Folder 460)
    See also: box 144, folder 709
  - Williams, Hinkley, 1828-1838 (Box 89, Folder 461)
    See also: box 144, folder 710-712
  - Williams, John
    - Account books, 1803-1807 (Box 89, Folder 462-463)
    - Daybook, 1788-1792 (Box 89, Folder 464)
    - Daybook, 1810-1814 (Box 90, Folder 465)
    - Loose papers, 1804 (Box 90, Folder 466)
  - Williams, Levi
    See: box 145, folder 715
  - Williams, Warham, 1814-1852 (Box 90, Folder 467)
  - Willing and Francis, 1753-1826 (Box 90, Folder 468)
    See also: box 146, folder 716
  - Willing and Shippen
    See: box 147, folder 717
  - Windham Cotton Manufacturing Company
    - Daybook, 1852-1857 (Box 91, Folder 469)
    - Ledger, 1823-1824 (Box 91, Folder 470)
  - Witterwell, [ ____ ], 1891 (Box 92, Folder 471)
  - Wolcott, James and Company
    See: box 148, folder 718
  - Woodford, Camp and Company
    See also: box 719-720
    - Accounts, 1883-1894 (Box 92, Folder 472)
    - Loose papers, 1833-1896 (Box 92, Folder 473)
  - Woodford, E.S., 1849-1870 (Box 92, Folder 474)
  - Woodin, Charles, 1840, undated (Box 92, Folder 475)
    See also: box 148, folder 722
  - Wooley, William
    See: box 148, folder 723
  - [Wyman, Proctor and Company?], 1847-1848 (Box 93, Folder 476)
  - Yale, Abel, 1812-1845 (Box 93, Folder 477)
  - Yale, Ira
    - Accounts, 1823-1833 (Box 93, Folder 478)
    - Loose papers, 1823-1833 (Box 93, Folder 479)
  - Yale, Samuel, 1800-1821 (Box 93, Folder 480)
  - Unidentified
    - New Haven, rum merchant, 1778 (Box 94, Folder 481)
    - Ledger, 1790 (Box 94, Folder 482)
    - New England merchant, 1793-1808 (Box 94, Folder 483)
    - New Haven, 1802-1804 (Box 94, Folder 484)
    - Derby, CT, 1803-1821 (Box 94, Folder 485)
    - Merchant, 1809-1810 (Box 94, Folder 486)
    - Litchfield, CT merchant
      See: box 149, folder 724
    - Watertown, or Waterbury CT, merchant, 1814-1815 (Box 95, Folder 487)
    - Weaver, 1814-1815 (Box 95, Folder 488)
    - Heath, MA (Box 95, Folder 489)
    - Record of Management
      See: box 149, folder 725
    - Derby, CT blacksmith, 1821-1847 (Box 95, Folder 490)
    - Ledger
      See: box 149, folder 726
    - Lyme, CT grocer, 1824-1825 (Box 96, Folder 491)
    - Daybook
      See: box 149, folder 727
    - Sterling, CT merchant, 1827-1888 (Box 96, Folder 492)
    - New Haven, CT shoemaker, 1828-1830 (Box 96, Folder 493)
    - North Haven, CT general store
      See: box 149, folder 728
    - [Southington, CT] merchant, 1831 (Box 96, Folder 494)
    - Ledger, 1836-1839 (Box 97, Folder 495)
    - Oxford, CT laborer and, 1838-1843 (Box 97, Folder 496)
    - Derby, CT general merchant
      See: box 150, folder 729
    - Branford, CT debt collector, 1838-1840 (Box 97, Folder 497)
    - Deep River, CT general merchant
      See: box 150, folder 730
    - Reading, CT general store
      See: box 150, folder 731
    - [Newtown, CT?] grocer and merchant
      See: box 151, folder 733-734
    - Marble Dale, CT farmer and teamster, 1843-1847 (Box 97, Folder 498)
    - Norwich, CT general merchant, 1843-1849 (Box 97, Folder 499)
    - [Waterbury, CT?] farmer and shoemaker
      See: box 151, folder 735
    - Warren, CT carpenter
      See: box 151. folder 736
    - Milford, CT farmer, 1845-1846 (Box 97, Folder 500)
      See: box 152. folder 737
    - Manchester, NH grocery store
      - Ledgers, 1849-1850 (Box 98, Folder 501-502)
      - Index to ledgers, 1850 (Box 98, Folder 503)
    - [New Haven, CT?] grain and oyster dealers, 1851-1874 (Box 98, Folder 504)
    - Easton, NY farmer, 1850-1860 (Box 98, Folder 505)
    - North Haven, CT general store?, 1852-1855 (Box 99, Folder 506)
    - Boston, MA cooper, 1855-1858 (Box 99, Folder 507)
    - Clinton, CT grocery and dry goods
      See: box 152, folder 738
    - Meriden, CT painting contractor, 1858-1860 (Box 99, Folder 508)
    - New Salem, MA
      - Daybook, 1865 (Box 99, Folder 509)
      - Ledger, 1865-1866 (Box 99, Folder 510)
    - Meriden, CT farmer and hardware dealer, 1873-1875 (Box 99, Folder 511)
    - Collinsville, CT domestic accounts, 1874-1885 (Box 100, Folder 512)
    - Derby, CT general store
      See: box 152, folder 739
    - Derby, CT inventory, 1887-1889 (Box 100, Folder 513)
    - New Haven, CT household accounts, 1892-1897 (Box 100, Folder 514)
    - New Haven, CT invoices
      See: box 152, folder 740
- OVERSIZED VOLUMES, 1706-1903; Series II; 29 linear feet (53 boxes)
  This series contains business accounts and financial records arranged in alphabetical order by the name of the individual and/or corporate body.
  Unidentified volumes (boxes 149-152) are arranged in approximate chronological order and, whenever possible, identified by the geographic location and type of volume.
  - Adams, Joseph, 1803-1826 (Box 100A, Folder 512A)
    See also: box 1, folder 5
  - Averill, Daniel, 1763-1842 (Box 100A, Folder 513A)
  - Babcock, Oliver, 1819-1852 (Box 100A, Folder 514A)
  - Barlow, D.S. and J.H., 1860-1863 (Box 100B, Folder 515)
  - Bassett, Ellsworth F., 1870-1874 (Box 100B, Folder 516)
    See also: box 4, folder 18
  - Bassett, Harvey D.
    See also: box 5, folder 21
    - Ledgers, 1849-1866 (Box 101, Folder 517-519)
    - Ledgers, 1852-1875 (Box 102, Folder 520-522)
    - Ledgers, 1877-1884 (Box 103, Folder 523-524)
  - Beecher, Lewis, 1813-1827 (Box 103, Folder 525)
    See also: box 5, folder 25
  - Belcher, William, 1827-1832 (Box 103, Folder 526)
  - Booth Charles, 1826-1847 (Box 103, Folder 527)
  - Bradley, Elisha, 1788-1821 (Box 103, Folder 528)
    See also: box 7, folder 38
  - Bradley and Wadsworth
    See also: box 8, folder 41-42
    - Daybooks, 1811-1817 (Box 104, Folder 529-530)
    - Daybooks, 1817-1822 (Box 105, Folder 531-533)
    - Daybook, 1825 (Box 106, Folder 534)
    - Ledger, 1808-1817 (Box 106, Folder 535)
    - Ledger, 1820-1827 (Box 107, Folder 536)
  - Brainerd, Elijah Newell, 1877-1886 (Box 107, Folder 537)
    See also: box 8-11, folder 43-47
  - Brandagee, Elishama
    - Account book, 1817, 1822 (Box 107, Folder 538)
    - Daybook, 1819-1829 (Box 107, Folder 539)
    - "Pedlar's Book", 1828-1856 (Box 108, Folder 540)
  - Brockway, Charles Hallam, 1834-1848 (Box 108, Folder 541-542)
    See also: box 11, folder 76-77
  - Browne, Francis (sloop Speedwell ), 1706-1716 (Box 108, Folder 543)
  - Bryan, Samuel, 1780-1828, 1866-1878 (Box 108, Folder 544)
  - Camp, David, 1798-1835 (Box 108, Folder 545)
    See also: box 13, folder 90
  - Carpenter, Gerald, 1816-1825 (Box 108, Folder 546)
  - Chatfield, Gideon, 1793-1827 (Box 108, Folder 547)
  - Chester, Edwin, 1827-1838 (Box 109, Folder 548)
  - Chittenden, K.S. and V.A., 1864-1866 (Box 109, Folder 549)
    See also: box 15, folder 103
  - Clark, Asahel, 1824-1859 (Box 109, Folder 550)
    See laso: box 16, folder 105
  - Clark, David Smith, 1808-1829 (Box 109, Folder 551)
    See also: box 16, folder 106
  - Cole, Nichols, and Company, 1837-1848 (Box 109, Folder 552)
  - Cook, John, 1837-1872 (Box 110, Folder 553)
    See also: box 17, folder 22
  - Cook, Thaddeus, 1758-1802 (Box 110, Folder 554)
  - Crane, Harrison, 1847-1862 (Box 110A, Folder 555)
  - Davis, James, 1805-1835 (Box 110A, Folder 556)
  - Delameter, Jacob, 1790-1810 (Box 110A, Folder 557)
  - Dewey, Christopher, 1798-1800 (Box 110A, Folder 558)
    See also: box 21, folder 139
  - Dexter, Normand, 1819-1826 (Box 110B, Folder 559)
  - Dickerman, Chauncey Alling, 1856-1861 (Box 110B, Folder 560)
  - Doolittle, Daniel, 1774-1808 (Box 111, Folder 561)
  - Dowd, C.H. and Company, 1852-1853 (Box 111, Folder 562)
    See also: box 22, folder 152
  - Dowd, Thomas, 1838-1849 (Box 111, Folder 563)
    See also: box 23, folder 153
  - Dowd, T.W. (Thomas W.), 1853-1857 (Box 111, Folder 564-566)
    See also: box 23, folder 154
  - Dowd, T.W. and C.H.
    - Daybooks, 1837-1853 (Box 112, Folder 567-570)
    - Daybooks, 1849-1852 (Box 112, Folder 571-572)
  - Dowd, T.W. and Company, 1851-1852 (Box 112, Folder 573-574)
    See also: box 23, folder 155
  - Dutton, Henry, 1835-1860 (Box 112, Folder 575-576)
    See also: box 26, folder 167
  - Eagle Bank (New Haven, CT)
    See also: box 26, folder 170-171
    - Cash disbursements journal, 1818-1820 (Box 112, Folder 577)
    - Ledger, 1818-1823 (Box 113, Folder 578)
  - Edmond, Loevy, 1818-1828 (Box 114, Folder 579)
  - Edwards, Pierpont, 1783-1793 (Box 114, Folder 580)
  - Farnum, Asa, 1831-1833 (Box 114, Folder 581)
  - Ford, Elias, 1794-1834 (Box 114, Folder 582)
    See also: box 29, folder 187
  - Frisbie, Samuel, 1793-1845 (Box 114, Folder 583)
  - Gillette, Henry S.; and Watson, Wellington, and Sons, 1843, 1848 (Box 115, Folder 584)
  - Grant, Clark Howe, 1859-1891 (Box 115, Folder 585-587)
    See also: box 33, folder 202
  - Green, Nathaniel, 1714-1733 (Box 115, Folder 588)
  - Griswold, Leverett, 1835-1841 (Box 115, Folder 589)
    See also: box 35, folder 209
  - Hall, Benjamin, 1796, 1798 (Box 116, Folder 590-591)
  - Hawkins, Abijah, 1831-1834, 1842-1849 (Box 116, Folder 592-593)
    See also: box 36, folder 217-218
  - Hayden and Company, 1824-1828 (Box 116, Folder 594)
  - Hemingway, Samuel and Company
    See also: box 37, folder 221-222
    - Cashbook, 1862-1878 (Box 117, Folder 595)
    - Daybooks, 1857-1866 (Box 117, Folder 596-599)
    - Daybook, 1866-1869 (Box 118, Folder 600)
    - Ledger, 1857-1858 (Box 118, Folder 601)
  - Hemingway, Willis and Sons Company, 1894-1903 (Box 118, Folder 602-603)
    See also: box 37, folder 223
  - Hendee, Lucius Justin
    See also: box 38, folder 224
    - Ledgers, 1835-1847 (Box 119, Folder 604-605)
    - Ledger, 1847-1858 (Box 120, Folder 606)
  - Hicock, Benjamin S. and Company, 1875-1876 (Box 121, Folder 607)
  - Hide, Abigail (Ogden), 1792-1810 (Box 122, Folder 608)
  - Hinman and Osborn, 1744-1776 (Box 122, Folder 609)
  - Hinsdale, Jacob, 1723-1774 (Box 122, Folder 610)
    See also: box 41, folder 235
  - Hopkins, John, 1776-1847 (Box 122, Folder 611)
  - Hubbard, Daniel, 1837-1869 (Box 122, Folder 612)
    See also: box 43, folder 240
  - Hulme, Christopher, 1828-1848 (Box 122, Folder 613)
    See also: box 44
  - Humphreys and Spencer, 1826-1828 (Box 123, Folder 614)
  - Huntington, Wolcott, 1826 (Box 124, Folder 615)
  - Johnson, David, 1795-1837 (Box 124, Folder 616)
    See also: box 45, folder 258
  - [Kimberly, Hobart?], 1856-1858 (Box 124, Folder 617)
    See also: box 47, folder 266
  - Lamb, Joseph
    See also: box 272
    - Account books, 1840-1855 (Box 125, Folder 618-619)
    - Daybook, 1840 (Box 125, Folder 620)
  - Learned, Edward
    See also: box 49, folder 279-280
    - Daybooks, 1811-1831 (Box 125, Folder 621-625)
    - Daybooks, 1831-1847 (Box 126, Folder 626-627)
    - Ledgers, 1811-1834 (Box 126, Folder 628-629)
  - Leavenworth, Andrew, 1792-1820 (Box 126, Folder 630)
  - Lee, James E., 1825-1875 (Box 126, Folder 631)
  - Leete, Morris Atwell
    See also: box 50, folder 283
    - Daybook, 1860-1864 (Box 127, Folder 632)
    - Ledger, 1824-1864 (Box 127, Folder 633)
  - Limburner, John, Jr., 1809-1834 (Box 127, Folder 634)
    See also: box 50, folder 284
  - Litchfield, Lorenzo, 1824-1852 (Box 127, Folder 635)
    See also: box 50, folder 288
  - Litchfield, CT, 1804-1809 (Box 127, Folder 636)
  - Lockwood, David, 1834-1877 (Box 127, Folder 637)
  - Lyman, David, 1771-1815 (Box 128, Folder 638)
    See also: box 51, folder 291
  - McCracken and Merriman
    See also: box 51, folder 292
    - Daybooks, 1813-1817, 1840-1842 (Box 128, Folder 639-640)
    - Daybook, 1844-1846 (Box 129, Folder 641)
    - Ledgers, 1820-1845 (Box 129, Folder 642-643)
    - Ledger, 1825-1833 (Box 130, Folder 644)
    - Ledger, 1839-1851 (Box 131, Folder 645)
  - McCulloch, Don Juan, 1879-1880 (Box 132, Folder 646)
    See also: box 51, folder 293
  - Meech, Thomas and Stephen, 1794-1859 (Box 133, Folder 647-650)
    See also: box 55-56, folder 305
  - Merwin, Anson, 1822-1857 (Box 133, Folder 651)
  - Miles, Stephen
    See also: box 56, folder 313
    - Daybook and post office accounts, 1826-1827, 1870-1871 (Box 133, Folder 652)
    - Ledger, 1826-1827 (Box 133, Folder 653)
  - Mix, William, 1792-1820 (Box 134, Folder 654)
  - Morehouse, Minor, 1821-1851 (Box 134, Folder 655)
  - Morse, Ebenezer, 1806-1827 (Box 134, Folder 656)
  - Mosley, Jeremiah
    See also: box 57, folder 316
    - Account book, 1825-1868 (Box 134, Folder 657)
    - Ledger, 1813-1827 (Box 134, Folder 658)
  - Mott, General Samuel, 1799-1812 (Box 135, Folder 659)
  - Mumford, Stephen, 1741-1744 (Box 135, Folder 660)
  - Norwalk, CT, 1794-1810 (Box 135, Folder 662)
  - Noyes; George W. and Company
    - Daybook, 1831 (Box 135, Folder 663)
    - Daybooks, 1831-1833 (Box 136, Folder 664-665)
  - Osborn, Ambrose, 1795-1853 (Box 136, Folder 666)
    See also: box 57, folder 321
  - [Palmer, Charles?], 1870-1874 (Box 136, Folder 667)
    See also: box 57, folder 322
  - Nashua Iron Company, 1855-1863 (Box 135, Folder 661)
  - Peck, Bennitt, 1817-1844 (Box 136, Folder 668)
  - Peck, Hayden G., 1825-1835 (Box 136, Folder 669)
  - Peck, Henry L., and Henry Smith Peck, and Peck and Somers
    See also: box 60, folder 335
    - "Bill book", 1848-1850 (Box 136, Folder 670)
    - Daybooks, 1829-1831, 1853-1868 (Box 137, Folder 671-673)
  - Peck, Joseph, 1786-1837 (Box 137, Folder 674-676)
  - Pierce, Joel, 1795-1872 (Box 138, Folder 677)
  - Pond, Henry
    See also: box 62, folder 344
    - Journal, 1844-1845 (Box 138, Folder 678)
    - Journal, 1848-1850 (Box 139, Folder 679)
    - Ledger, 1831-1833 (Box 139, Folder 680)
  - Richmond, George, 1847 (Box 139, Folder 681)
  - Rockwell, Thomas, 1820-1859 (Box 139, Folder 682)
  - Root, Charles, 1854, 1856 (Box 139, Folder 683)
    See also: box 64, folder 356
  - Russell, Lewis, 1806-1807 (Box 139, Folder 684)
    See also: box 65, folder 359
  - Safford, William, 1843-1853 (Box 139, Folder 685)
  - Schleiter, H.L., 1857-1862 (Box 139, Folder 686)
  - Seaman, John, 1818-1820 (Box 140, Folder 687)
  - Shelton, Joseph, 1728-1789 (Box 140, Folder 688)
    See also: box 67, folder 369
  - Smith, Isaac, John, and George H., 1803-1806, 1831-1837 (Box 140, Folder 689)
    See also: box 68, folder 371
  - Smith, William R., 1841-1862 (Box 140, Folder 690-691)
    See also: box 69, folder 378
  - Smith and Cottrell, 1858 (Box 141, Folder 692)
    See also: box 70, folder 380
  - Steele, Norman, 1804-1839 (Box 141, Folder 693)
  - Tallmadge, John and Company
    See also: box 73, folder 390
    - Ledger, 1800-1802 (Box 141, Folder 694)
    - Ledger, 1807 (Box 142, Folder 695)
  - Thompson, Moses, 1806-1822 (Box 142, Folder 696)
  - Tweedy, R. and S., 1809-1822 (Box 142, Folder 697)
  - Underhill, Richardson, 1800-1802 (Box 142, Folder 698)
  - U.S. Army Collection, 1780-1783 (Box 142, Folder 699)
  - Vose, Nathan, 1805-1832 (Box 143, Folder 700)
  - Wadsworth, Elijah and Company, 1801-1805 (Box 143, Folder 701)
  - Washband, Josiah, 1803-1857 (Box 143, Folder 702)
  - W. Watson and Sons, 1868-1871 (Box 143, Folder 703-704)
  - Webb (Walter) and Company, 1850-1853 (Box 143, Folder 705)
  - Whitney and Townshend, 1846 (Box 144, Folder 706)
  - William, Amos, 1811-1834 (Box 144, Folder 707-708)
  - Williams, Harmon, 1795-1847 (Box 144, Folder 709)
    See also: box 89, folder 460
  - Williams, Hinckley
    See also: box 89, folder 461
    - Daybooks, 1828-1833 (Box 144, Folder 710-712)
    - Daybooks, 1833-1836, 1841-1845 (Box 145, Folder 713-714)
  - Williams, Levi, 1820-1824 (Box 145, Folder 715)
  - Willing and Francis, 1812-1859 (Box 146, Folder 716)
    See also: box 90, folder 468
  - Willing and Shippen, 1729-1740 (Box 147, Folder 717)
  - Wolcott, James and Company, 1814 (Box 148, Folder 718)
  - Woodford, Camp and Company
    See also: box 92, folder 472
    - Daybooks, 1881-1900 (Box 148, Folder 719-720)
    - Index and miscellaneous accounts, 1898-1903 (Box 148, Folder 721)
  - Woodin, Charles, 1823-1864 (Box 148, Folder 722)
    See also: box 92, folder 475
  - Wooley, William, 1732-1761 (Box 148, Folder 723)
  - Unidentified
    - Litchfield, CT merchant, 1812-1813 (Box 149, Folder 724)
    - Record of management, 1820-1844 (Box 149, Folder 725)
    - Ledger, 1821-1826 (Box 149, Folder 726)
    - Daybook, 1824-1825 (Box 149, Folder 727)
    - North Haven, CT general store, 1830-1831 (Box 149, Folder 728)
    - Derby, CT general merchant, 1838-1839 (Box 150, Folder 729)
    - Deep River, CT general merchant, 1840-1860 (Box 150, Folder 730)
    - Reading, CT general store
      - Daybook, 1841-1843 (Box 150, Folder 731)
      - Daybook, 1842-1843 (Box 151, Folder 732)
    - [Newtown, CT?] grocer and merchant, 1843 (Box 151, Folder 733-734)
    - [Waterbury, CT?] farmer and shoemaker, 1843-1861 (Box 151, Folder 735)
    - Warren, CT carpenter, 1844-1892 (Box 151, Folder 736)
    - Milford, CT general merchant, 1845-1846 (Box 152, Folder 737)
      See also: box 97, folder 500
    - Clinton, CT grocery and dry goods, 1858-1859 (Box 152, Folder 738)
    - Derby, CT general store, 1876-1877 (Box 152, Folder 739)
    - New Haven, CT invoices, 1896-1897 (Box 152, Folder 740)
- NUMERICAL, 1786-1925; Series III; 3.5 linear feet (9 boxes)
  This series contains business accounts and financial records arranged in numerical order, by volume number. Each volume is assigned a number and, whenever possible, is identified by the individual and/or corporate owner, the geographic location, and the type of volume.
  - NUMERICAL, 1-21
    - No. 1: Longfellow Literary Association, N.Y.: treasurer's records, 1870-1877 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - No. 2: Brubacher, John Seiler: journal of expenses during first year of marriage, Troy, N.Y., 1924-1925 (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - No. 3:
      See: Numerical Oversize, box 162
    - No. 4: G & H Company, Boston: invoice and letterbook, 1825-1829, 1848 (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - No. 5: Unidentified [New Haven grocer?]: account book, scrapbook, 1840, 1864 (Box 153, Folder 4)
    - No. 6: Blanchard, Amos: boarding accounts for students of Phillips Academy, Andover, Massachusetts, 1819-1829 (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - No. 7: Cooke, Increase & Company, New Haven [bookseller]: exchange book, 1804-1808 (Box 154, Folder 6)
      See also: box 161, folder 21
    - No. 8: Southworth, Edward Wells: accounts of his estate, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - No. 9: [Crowell, T. N.]: ledger kept by a Connecticut hardware merchant, with accounts for boarders and employees, 1843-1862 (Box 154, Folder 7)
    - No. 10: Unidentified account book, in German, re: sale of cloth, 1790-1793 (Box 154, Folder 8)
    - No. 11: Newton, Edmund [Brookfield, Connecticut]: account book, poems, songs, miscellaneous writings, 1786-1814, undated (Box 155, Folder 9)
    - No. 12: Morse, William W. [New Haven printer]: daybook, scrapbook, 1800-1802 (Box 155, Folder 10)
    - No. 13: Watrous, George Stone: account book kept in kobe, Japan, 1900-1908 (Box 155, Folder 11)